Register of the Bunin family papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Bunin family papers
1795-1962
90075
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.7 linear feet)
Writings, certificates, photographs, postcards, and miscellany relating to social conditions and rural life in Russia before the Russian Revolution, Russian émigré life in France and the United States, and activities of the right-wing Russian émigré group Mladorosskaia Partiia in France between the two world wars.
Bunin family.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Family of Boris Ivanovich Bunin, Russian émigrés in France and the United States.
Scope and Content of Collection
Comprised of writings, certificates, photographs, postcards, and miscellany relating to social conditions and rural life in Russia before the Russian Revolution, Russian émigré life in France and the United States, and activities of the right-wing Russian émigré group Mladorosskaia Partiia in France between the two world wars.
Bunin, Boris Ivanovich.; Mladorosskaia partiia.; Fascism--France.; Russia--Social conditions.; Russians--France.; Russians--United States.
- Boris Ivanovich Bunin Writings, 1903-1962
  - Poetical works, 1903-1911 (Box-folder 1:1-7)
  - Teorema Ferma, 1913-1962 (Box-folder 1:8)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes manuscript, printed copy, and correspondence regarding the registration of a copyright.
- Ivan Mikhailovich Bunin File, 1917 (Box-folder 1:9)
  Includes education certificates.
- Sof'ia Mikhailovna Bunina File, 1906-1953 (Box-folder 1:10)
  Includes education certificate and pictures of classmates.
- Vsevolod Borisovich Bunin File, 1914-1932 (Box-folder 1:11)
  Includes birth certificate and gymnasium diploma.
- Photographs, 1881-1945
  - 281 prints, 1881-1933 (Boxes 2-4)
    Depicting members of the Bunin family, landowners, peasants, and scenes of rural life in early twentieth century Russia.
  - 27 prints, undated (Box 4)
    Depicting Tsar Alexander III, Tsar Nicholas II, and other members of the Romanov family.
  - 15 prints, undated (Box 4)
    Depicting Russian military officers from World War I and the Russian Revolution, and the bodies of famine victims during the Russian Revolution.
  - 50 prints and postcards, undated (Box 4)
    Depicting historic buildings and landmarks in Russia and various countries of Europe.
  - 44 prints, circa 1914-1945 (Box 4)
    Depicting Russian emigres in France, including members of the Bunin family and of the Romanov family.
  - 22 prints, circa 1914-1945 (Box 4)
    Depicting members of the right-wing Russian emigre group Mladorosskaia Partiia in France.
- Printed matter: Slovar' natural'nago volshebstva, Moscow, 1795 (Box 3)